Guide to the Tennesse Williams Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Works by Others
  - Bachardy Don; Bennet, Penelope Agnes Drawing; 2 short stories, [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Bernstein, Walter Front, The, [n.p.], August 13, 1975, (1 Screenplay revised) (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Bowles, Paul Without Stopping [autobiography], [n.p.], 1972, (1 Uncorrected proof ) (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Braden, A; Brainard, Joe; Brandes, C. Simon Drawings, [n.p.], 1971, n.d., () (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Brown, Dawn and Sterling Prints and short stories, [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Brown, Frank Chouteau Dwellings of Newbury Old Town, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 article printed in The Monograph Series) (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Burkhart, Brian Georgia 1934, [n.p.], 1970, (Song lyrics) (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Burke, Patricia K. Weary Purple Mums [short story], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Capobianco, Marc The Love Story of Big Daddy's Poshlost [play], [n.p.], 1978, () (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Carrie, Jacques Bridge of Movie Producer Louis King, [n.p.], 1981, (Review proofs of novel) (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Calisher, Hortense False Entry, [n.p.], 1961, (Uncorrected proof of novel) (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Carroll, Robert Several works, [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 34, Folder 3-7)
  - Carroll, Robert Several works, [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
  - Castro, Virginia With Whom Did Christina Lose Her Virginity? [play], [n.p.], 1979, () (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Chekhov, Anton The Gull [play translated by Wendel Agne], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Cobelle; Cocteau, Jean; Coply, William J. Drawings, Calendar, [n.p.], [n.d.], 1979, () (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Congdon, Kirby Magazine Four, 1969, (1 magazine edited by Congdon) (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Corbeil, Michel Meet me at the Automat [One-act], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Darrid, William The Long Way Home. Hart Crane [screenplay], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - De Luca, Angelo Romancement, [n.p.], 1968, (Pamphlet of poem) (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Derwent, Clarence Red Beard [play], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Dickman, Kenneth George Axiomatic Smiles, [n.p.], 1980, (Short stories) (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Dunphy, Jack Nightmovers, [n.p.], 1968, (Proof of novel) (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Dunphy, Jack Saturday Night Kid [play], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Evans, Oliver Terminal Station [short story], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Hintz, Evelyn Mosaic, 1980, (1 journal ) (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Hoffman, Jill Journey to the Day [play], [n.p.], 1976, () (Box 36, Folder 3)
    [ First draft]
  - Hood, Henry Dinner at Antoine's, [n.p.], (1 Treatment) (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Hotchkis, Joan Last Roundup [short story], [n.p.], 1981, () (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Hutchison, Stuart Just Before the Dawn [one-man play], [n.p.], 1978-1980, () (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Kayopoulos, Denis Coming Home [play], [n.p.], 1980, () (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Kingsley-Smith,Terry Catholic Hour [novel], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Kroll, Leon; Krause, Franka Caricature of Williams; My Maiden Fair, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Drawing; sheet music) (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Lambert, Gavin Inside Daisy Clover, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Unrevised proof) (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Leverich, Lyle Julian and Maddalo, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Treatment for a teleplay series) (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Lewis, M. K. Locust Lane [play], [n.p.], 1982, () (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Lyndon, Andrew Acting Out [play], [n.p.], 1977, () (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Lowe, Jim Gather Round, Children [play], [n.p.], 1981, () (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Malanga, Gerard Where Else Can We Go to Escape from the Shimmering Chalice [poem], [n.p.], 1965, () (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Maugham, W. Somerset Outstation [play], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Spencer Carr Carson McCullers and the Search for Meaning [dissertation], [n.p.], 1969, () (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Works by and about Carson McCullers, [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 37, Folder 4)
    [Includes The Square Root of Wonderful and Art and Mr. Mahoney]
  - Works by and about Carson McCullers, 1962, (1 reprint of article "The Achievement of Carson McCullers" by Oliver Evans) (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - McCulloch, Samuel C. Feast of Sant Urbano [play], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - McGuane, Thomas Bushwhacked Piano, [n.p.], 1972, (Advance uncorrected proof) (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Merten, Julie Diane Scrapbook, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Photographs, poems, essays, drawings) (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Minoca [?]; Mitrovich, Marta Drawing of Frank Merlo; Play, [n.p.], [n.d.] & 1968, () (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Nikolov, Nikola Short stories, [n.p.], 1978, () (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Nizer, Louis Chapter From My Life in Court, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Memoir) (Box 38, Folder 3-4)
  - Ozag, Lisa Spellbound The Red River [poetry], [n.p.], 1977-1979, () (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Paglia, James Summer Ennui [play], [n.p.], 1981, () (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Parks, Jarvin Selected Poems, [n.p.], 1967, (Booklet of poems) (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Perret, Edmund Red Rocker Light [short story], [n.p.], 1980, () (Box 38, Folder 8)
    [Inscribed by author]
  - Pinckert, Francine Knight's Landing, [n.p.], 1967, (Unrevised proof) (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Ramington, John Poems for Private Distribution, [n.p.], 1971, () (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Rasky, Harry No Big Deal [play], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Rasky, Harry Nobody Swings on Sunday [memoir], [n.p.], [n.d.], (149 pages (1-149)) (Box 38, Folder 12)
    [With introduction by Tennessee Williams]
  - Rasky, Harry Nobody Swings on Sunday [memoir], [n.p.], [n.d.], (41 pages (150-591)) (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
  - Rayman, Robert Bedrock [play], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Rorem, Ned Pastry Shop, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Monolog-Burlesque) (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Sexton, Anne Live or Die [book of poetry], [n.p.], 1966, () (Box 39, Folder 5)
    [Published by Houghton Mifflin Co., Boston]
  - Schulberg, Budd From the Ashes, [n.p.], 1967, (1 Copy of introduction) (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Silbert, Eve Stranieri [short story], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Smith, William Jay Straw Market and Tall Poets, [n.p.], 1966-1979, (Play and Poem) (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Sorrentino, Gilbert Neon, [n.p.], n.d., (Literary magazine) (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Stewart, Joe B. Mindfucke, [n.p.], 1968, (Magazine) (Box 39, Folder 10)
    [Inscribed by editor]
  - Stewart, Joe B. The Circle, 1968, (1 magazine inscribed by Stewart) (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Tchelitchew, Pavel and Thom, Robert Drawing; Play, [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Thompson, Ernest Lessons [play], [n.p.], 1978, () (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Tillinghast, Richard Sewanee in Ruins [poems], [n.p.], 1982, () (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Torres, A. M. Infinite Intermezzo, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Novel) (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Trocchi, Alexander Cain's Book, [n.p.], 1960, (Uncorrected proof) (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Turner, Dennis Give my Regards to Broadway [play], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Vaccaro, Marion Black Poem book, [n.p.], 1974, () (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Vass, Viola Veidt, Frank Ventgen and Vertes [drawings, poster, story], [n.p.], [1979-1981, n.d.], () (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Welty, Eudora Why I Live at the P.O. [play], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Williams, Dakin Walter Short stories, [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Wilson, Julia Homer; Donald Windham, Workman, Chuck Drawing; Program; Screenplay, [n.p.], [1971 & n.d.], () (Box 40, Folder 10)
    [Program for The Starless Air, May 13, 1943 is acq. 304754]
  - Yates, Richard Eleven Kinds of Loneliness [short stories], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Yoo, Chi-jen Korean paperback, n.d., () (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Youghn, Pat Writings, [n.p.], 1977-1978, () (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Young, Frederic Many Ingenious Lovely Things [novel], [n.p.], [n.d.], () (Box 41, Folder 3 & 4)
  - Young, Marguerite Miss McIntosh, My Darling, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Reviews of novel) (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified writings, drawings and poems, [n.p.], [n.d.], (7 folders) (Box 41, Folder 6-12)
  - Unidentified writings, drawings and poems, [n.p.], [n.d.], (11 folders) (Box 42, Folder 1-11)
- Series V: Photographs
  This series contains snapshots as well as professional and news photographs of Tennessee Williams, his family, and friends. In particular, there are many pictures of Williams' longtime companion, Frank Merlo, and of his close friend, Maria Britneva St. Just. There are also photographs of productions and of celebratory events, as well as works by professional photographers and stills from 1950s MGM productions.
  - Subseries V.1: Personal & Professional
    - Tennessee Williams and Friends, [v.p.], 1900s-1980s, (56 photographs) (Box 43, Folder 1)
      [Williams as child and young man [acq 293/4 Jan 1990]; with Herbert Machiz at Gotham Book Mart [acq 599624];Williams, photos sent by Frederick Nicklaus [acq 490 (Mixer)/6 Sept 1983]; various photos of Williams with actors, friends colleagues including group 1948 picture at the Gotham Book Mart [acq 293 10 27 83]]
    - Tennessee Williams, [v.p.], 1910s - 1982, (137 photographs & prints) (Box 43, Folder 2 and 3)
    - Tennessee Williams and pets, [v.p.], 1950s-1970s, (68 photographs) (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Key West House, [Key West, FL], [n.d.], (10 photographs) (Box 43, Folder 5)
      [Of Key West house, hurricane damage, and art]
    - Thomas Lanier Williams II, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 framed photograph, torn) (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Walter Edwin Dakin, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 framed photograph) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Walter Edwin Dakin, [n.p.], 1900s-1950s, (18 photographs ) (Box 44, Folder 2)
      [Of grandfather Dakin, some with wife Rosina Dakin and friends]
    - Williams and Dakin families, [v.p.], [v.d.], (14 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Edwina Dakin Williams, mother Rosina Dakin and family, [n.p.], 1900s-1980, (16 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Rose Williams, [n.p.], 1910s-1978, (12 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Dakin Williams and family, [n.p.], 1960s, (4 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Frank Merlo, [n.p.], 1940s-1960s, (158 photographs, 25 negatives) (Box 44, Folder 7-8)
      [Negatives of Merlo, some with Williams and friends]
    - Frank Merlo, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photo scrapbook) (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Maria Britneva St. Just, family and Williams, [n.p.], 1940s-1980s, (27 photographs) (Box 45, Folder 2)
      [St. Just, some with family and Williams]
    - St. Just with daughters, [n.p.], 1960s, (1 framed photgraph) (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Tennessee Williams and friends, [n.p.], 1940s-1970s, (298 photographs, 4 negatives) (Box 45, Folder 4-6)
      [Of Williams, family, friends, artists, and celebrities]
    - Tennessee Williams, [n.p.], 1940s-1980s, (160 photographs) (Box 46, Folder 1-3)
      [Of Williams, family, artists, celebrities, and events]
    - Artists, [n.p.], 1950s-1980s, (63 photographs) (Box 46, Folder 4)
      [Of writers, actresses, painters, etc. including Truman Capote, Elizabeth Ashley, Christopher Isherwood, Anna Magnani, Anne Meacham, Sylvia Miles, Eugene O'Neill, Geraldine Page, Anthony Quinn, Johnny Ray, Laurette Taylor and Michael York]
    - Actor glossies, [n.p.], 1960s-1980s, (56 photographs) (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Subseries V.2: Production Photographs
    - Camino Real, [New York], 1953, (9 photographs) (Box 46, Folder 6)
      [From original New York production]
    - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, New York, Italy, and France, 1950, 1982, (4 photographs ) (Box 46, Folder 7)
      [1 Original production; 3 of Roman and French production]
    - The Glass Menagerie, [v.p.], [n.d.], (7 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 1)
      [From several productions]
    - Ladies of Larkspur Lotion, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph) (Box 47, Folder 2)
      [ [acq Brander Matthews]]
    - Period of Adjustment, Sweden, [n.d.], (2 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 3)
      [From Swedish production]
    - Night of the Iguana, [New York], 1961, 1964, (8 photographs ) (Box 47, Folder 4)
      [From the original New York production and from the film]
    - Orpheus Descending, Australia and Greece, 1980-1981, (6 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Red Devil Battery Sign, Vancouver, BC, 1980-1981, (1 photograph) (Box 47, Folder 6)
      [Vancouver Playhouse production]
    - Rose Tattoo, [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Senso, [n.p.], 1954, (6 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Stairs to the Roof, Pasadena, CA, 1947, (6 photographs ) (Box 47, Folder 9)
      [From Pasadena Playhouse production]
    - Streetcar Named Desire, [n.p.], 1951-1980, (28 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 10)
      [From various productions]
    - Suddenly Last Summer, [n.p.], [n.d.], (5 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Summer and Smoke, Denmark, 1949, (1 photograph ) (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Sweet Bird of Youth, [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 13)
      [2 from original New York production [acq Brander Matthews]; 1 of production starring Ed Harris as Chance]
    - Twenty Seven Wagons Full of Cotton, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph) (Box 47, Folder 14)
      [From production starring Meryl Streep]
    - Two Character Play, [n.p.], [n.d.] and 1976, (2 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 15)
      [One from San Francisco production starring Fred Ward]
    - Vieux Carre, [n.p.], [n.d.], (13 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified Productions, [n.p.], [n.d.], (44 photographs) (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Icons, [n.p.], 1922, 1972, (1 framed photo of D. H. Lawrence) (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Icons, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 magazine prints of Hart Crane, 2 photographs of Marlene Dietrich, 3 inscribed photographs of Ernest Hemingway, 1 article on D. H. Lawrence, 1 photograph of Edna St. Vincent Millay) (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Art photography, [n.p.], [n.d.], (25 photographs and prints) (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Art Photography: Bill Viggiano, [n.p.], 1980, (33 photographs of the homeless with correspondence and notes, 2 photographs of scenes) (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Copies of photographs used in exhibits, [n.p.], [n.d.], (7 photographs of Tennessee Williams and productions) (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Subseries V.3: Film Stills
    - Various productions, [v.p.], 1920s-1950s, (46 photographs from various movies, mostly MGM productions) (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Conspirator, 1950, (5 stills) (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Beau Brummel, 1954, (34 stills) (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Deep In My Heart, 1954, (57 stills) (Box 48, Folder 6-8)
    - Devil Makes Three, 1952, (20 stills) (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Green Dolphin Street, 1955, (59 stills) (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Ivanhoe, 1952, (84 stills) (Box 49, Folder 2-3)
    - Kissing Bandit, 1948, (15 stills) (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Last Time I Saw Paris, 1954, (70 stills) (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Lili, 1952, (37 stills) (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Lovely To Look At, 1952, (98 stills) (Box 49, Folder 7-8)
    - Merton of the Movies, 1947, (7 stills) (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Please Believe Me, 1950, (31 stills) (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Romance of Rosy Ridge, 1947, (4 stills) (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Skipper Surprised His Wife, 1950, (27 stills) (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Tender Trap (1955); Unfinished Dance, (1947) 1947, 1955, (5 stills) (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Washington Story, 1952, (20 stills) (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Yellow Cab Man, 1950, (41 stills) (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Young Bess, 1953, (42 stills) (Box 50, Folder 8)
- Series VI: Audiotapes
  1960-1970 & undated. 0.5 linear ft.13 reel to reel audiotapes
  - Once Over Lightly, November 1, 1960; David Frost TV, January, 1970; An Evening with Tennessee Williams, Waterfront Playhouse, May 1, 1970 (2); Laugh In, Pt. I, n.d., 1960-1970, (6 reel to reel audiotapes) (Box 50)
  - Audiotapes: 2 unidentified, (2 reel to reel audiotapes) (Box Tape 1)
  - Audiotapes: In The Winter Of Cities read by David Lobdell; Tennessee Williams, Maureen Stapleton and other actors; 1 unidentified, (3 reel to reel audiotapes.) (Box Tape 2)
  - Audiotapes: Laurindo Almeida Spanish Guitars; Erich Leinsdorf, The Sound of Wagner, (2 reel to reels) (Box Tape 3)